{
    "id": "7cf229447eaf4bc688523a5e8eb39292",
    "title": "Past Simple Or Past Continuous Tense Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "a9474b433ab1418289c36809a615a455",
            "title": "Past Simple or Past Continuous Tense Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I .................... with my son when you ....................",
                    "description": "When we talk about two past events, the past continuous is normally used to refer to the longer background action. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "played, called",
                        "was playing, were calling",
                        "was playing, called",
                        "played, were calling"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The doorbell .................... while I ..................... a bath.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "rang, was having",
                        "was ringing, was having",
                        "was ringing. had"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "As I ........................ for bus, I ............................. Joe crossing the road.",
                    "description": "When we talk about two past events, the past continuous is normally used to refer to the longer background action. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "waited, saw",
                        "was waiting, saw",
                        "waited, was seeing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Yesterday, I ....................... to the movies with my wife.",
                    "description": "The simple past tense is the normal tense for talking about finished actions and situations. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "was going",
                        "went",
                        "had gone"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "When I was a child, we ................ our own amusements.",
                    "description": "The past continuous is not normally used for talking about repeating past actions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "were making",
                        "made",
                        "have made"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "When we .................... home, we discovered that water .......................... down the walls.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "reached, ran",
                        "reached, was running",
                        "was reaching, was running"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It ........................ while I .......................... in Mumbai.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was happening, was living",
                        "happened, was living",
                        "happened, lived"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I .................... in Rome for ten years while I ................. a child.",
                    "description": "We use the past simple to talk about longer situations in the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "lived, was",
                        "was living, was",
                        "lived, had been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ......................... all day yesterday.",
                    "description": "The past continuous can be used to suggest that an activity was in progress at every moment during a period of time. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "had slept",
                        "was sleeping"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "What ................................. at 11 pm last night?",
                    "description": "The past continuous is used to talk about actions or situations that were in progress at a particular point of time in the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "did you do",
                        "were you doing",
                        "had you done"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who .......................... you that watch?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was giving",
                        "gave",
                        "had given"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "When I ......................... into the office, everybody ...................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was walking",
                        "walked, worked",
                        "walked, was working"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}